Guide to the Archives Union File (AUF), Section 6: Boxes 319.1-378
Archives Union File (AUF), Section 6: Boxes 319.1-378
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 368, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Report of the Committee on Cultural Minorities - 1947 Convention of the American Federation, Publication (Box 368, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: Report of the Executive Council to the 29th Annual Convention of the American Federation of Teachers, Publication (Box 368, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: Report of the Committee on Organization, Publication (Box 368, Folder 5)
  - Item 4: Report of the Committee on Cultural Minorities, Publication (Box 368, Folder 5)
  - Item 5: Report on the American Teacher, 1945-1947 (Box 368, Folder 5)
    Notes: 1945-46; 1946-47
  - Item 6: Report of the Research Director, 1954-1955 (Box 368, Folder 5)
  - Item 7: The union in action in 1951, Publication (Box 368, Folder 5)
  - Item 8: Fringe benefits for teachers, 1958; Publication (Box 368, Folder 5)
  - Item 9: I. Survey of salaries paid in representative American universities and teacher training schools: II. Survey of salaries in the junior colleges in the United States, Publication (Box 368, Folder 5)
    Notes: Compiled from figures furnished by the presidents of the respective institutions. 2nd copy
  - Item 10: Merit rating: dangerous mirage or master plan, 1958; Publication (Box 368, Folder 5)
  - Item 11: Schedule of salary rate ranges for existing classifications minimum starting salaries, and salary levels of the automatic salary increase plan effective February 1, 1956, Publication (Box 368, Folder 5)
  - Item 12: Survey of Teachers Salaries, 1956-1957 (Box 368, Folder 5)
  - Item 13: Teacher Aides, 1958; Publication (Box 368, Folder 5)
  - Item 14: Television, tool for education or substitute, 1958; Publication (Box 368, Folder 5)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 368, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: A survey of 1954-55 teacher salary schedules in 893 U.S. cities with populations of 10,000 or over, 1955; Publication (Box 368, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: I. Survey of salaries paid in representative American universities and teacher training schools: II. Survey of salaries in the junior colleges in the United States, Publication (Box 368, Folder 6)
    Notes: Compiled from figures furnished by the presidents of the respective institutions
  - Item 3: The union in action, 1946-1949 (Box 368, Folder 6)
    Notes: 1946-1947, 1949
  - Item 4: A survey of 1955-56 teacher salary schedules in 933 U.S. cities with populations of 10,000 or over, 1956; Publication (Box 368, Folder 6)
  - Item 5: Survey of Teachers Salaries, 1957-1958 (Box 368, Folder 6)
    Notes: 1958, Suppl. 1958, 1957
  - Item 6: Education around the world, Publication (Box 368, Folder 6)
  - Item 7: Financial comparisons of public schools by states, Publication (Box 368, Folder 6)
  - Item 8: Salary data, paid school days, and fringe benefits for teachers on certain districts in America, Publication (Box 368, Folder 6)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 368, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: A tentative summary report for an effective schools program in urban centers, 1965; Publication (Box 368, Folder 7)
    Author: National Council for Effective Schools
  - Item 2: The challenging needs of vocational education: an AFL-CIO report to a Presidents Panel, Publication (Box 368, Folder 7)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: AFT Quest Report; AFT Quest Report on Differentiated staffing, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: AFT Quest Paper on new currents in education, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: AFT Quest Paper on collective bargaining and the teaching-learning process, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: AFT Quest Paper on a paradigm for accountability, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 1)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Financial statement, 1940-1941 (Box 368.1, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Financial statement, 1945-1946 (Box 368.1, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Financial statement, 1946-1947 (Box 368.1, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: Financial statement, 1947-1948 (Box 368.1, Folder 2)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Brotherhood Week, Negro history week, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 3)
  - Item 2: The English language is my enemy, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: Special Supplement/Negro History Month, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 3)
  - Item 4: Merit rating educationally unsound, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: The AFT and integration, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 3)
  - Item 6: AAUP and AFTwhich way for the Professors?, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 3)
  - Item 7: New Hope for City Schools, by Beatrice B. Gotthold, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 3)
  - Item 8: Why teachers need the AFL-CIO, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 3)
  - Item 9: Needed: more teacher strikes, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 3)
  - Item 10: Significance of the NYC Teachers Collective Bargaining Election, by Carl J. Megel, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 3)
  - Item 11: Neglected landmark: California's Jack Owens case, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 3)
  - Item 12: Teacher conscriptionbasis of association membership?, 1964; Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 3)
  - Item 13: Why the AFT maintains its AFL-CIO affiliation, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 3)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: A survey of 1954-55 teacher salary schedules in 893 U.S. cities with populations of 10,000 or over, 1955; Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 4)
  - Item 2: A survey of 1952-53 teacher salary schedules, 1952-1953 (Box 368.1, Folder 4)
  - Item 3: Salary schedules in representative American Cities, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: Evaluating guidance procedures, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 4)
  - Item 5: The status of equal job opportunity in America, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 4)
  - Item 6: Higher Education - Problems and Prospects, 1957-1970 (Box 368.1, Folder 4)
  - Item 7: Salary schedules in representative American Cities, 1950-1951 (Box 368.1, Folder 4)
  - Item 8: Report of the Research Director, 1954-1955 (Box 368.1, Folder 4)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Fringe benefits for teachers, 1958; Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: I. Survey of salaries paid in representative American universities and teacher training schools: II. Survey of salaries in the junior colleges in the United States, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: Merit rating: dangerous mirage or master plan, 1958; Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 5)
  - Item 4: Schedule of salary rate ranges for existing classifications minimum starting salaries, and salary levels of the automatic salary increase plan effective February 1, 1956, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 5)
  - Item 5: Survey of Teachers Salaries, 1956-1957 (Box 368.1, Folder 5)
  - Item 6: Teacher Aides, 1958; Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 5)
  - Item 7: Television, tool for education or substitute, 1958; Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 5)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: A survey of 1955-56 teacher salary schedules in 933 U.S. cities with populations of 10,000 or over, 1956; Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: Survey of Teachers Salaries, 1957-1958 (Box 368.1, Folder 6)
  - Item 3: Education around the world, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 6)
  - Item 4: Financial comparisons of public schools by states, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 6)
  - Item 5: Salary data, paid school days, and fringe benefits for teachers on certain districts in America, Publication (Box 368.1, Folder 6)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 369, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Fiscal independence versus fiscal dependence of school boards; a key to better schools, 1960; Publication (Box 369, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: Less than an egg a day; a study of the average salary of teachers, 1965-1966, Publication (Box 369, Folder 1)
    Author: Pete Schnaufer; Donald Burton
  - Item 3: Lunchroom supervision practices in cities of 500,000 population and up, Publication (Box 369, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: Necessity for student grouping in the public schools, Publication (Box 369, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: Higher Education - Problems and Prospects, 1957-1970 (Box 369, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: School dropouts and quality education, 1964; Publication (Box 369, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: School expenditures, tax rates, and assessed valuation in major cities, 1957; Publication (Box 369, Folder 1)
  - Item 8: Teacher Aides, 1958; Publication (Box 369, Folder 1)
  - Item 9: Television, tool for education or substitute, 1958; Publication (Box 369, Folder 1)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 369, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Teacher strikes and elections: a statistical survey of work stoppages and representation elections among classroom teachers, Publication (Box 369, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Would you believe, Publication (Box 369, Folder 2)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 369, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: A new tenure act, 1966; Publication (Box 369, Folder 3)
    Author: Mary Lee Leahy
  - Item 2: Credential reform in California, 1966; Publication (Box 369, Folder 3)
    Author: Ralph Schloming
  - Item 3: Programs to alter negative attitudes toward integration, 1970; Publication (Box 369, Folder 3)
    Author: George Henderson
  - Item 4: Shop class size survey and suggestions for vocational education reform, 1968; Publication (Box 369, Folder 3)
    Author: Morris Shapiro
  - Item 5: Statewide teacher retirement systems, 1968; Publication (Box 369, Folder 3)
    Author: W. William Schmid
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 369, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: A Nation-wide sample of classroom needs, revised, 1964; Publication (Box 369, Folder 4)
  - Item 2: A summary of districts providing fringe benefits for teachers, 1964; Publication (Box 369, Folder 4)
    Notes: Revised edition
  - Item 3: Current fears of teachers, Publication (Box 369, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: Evaluation of personnel practices in selected school systems, 1963; Publication (Box 369, Folder 4)
    Author: George s. reuter
  - Item 5: Examples of presentations to boards of education, 1963; Publication (Box 369, Folder 4)
  - Item 6: Payroll deduction, an AFT principle, 1963; Publication (Box 369, Folder 4)
  - Item 7: Per pupil cost in representative districts of America, 1964; Publication (Box 369, Folder 4)
    Notes: Revised edition. 2 copies
  - Item 8: Shared time, 1963; Publication (Box 369, Folder 4)
  - Item 9: The 88th Congress, Publication (Box 369, Folder 4)
  - Item 10: The defined school year, 1963; Publication (Box 369, Folder 4)
  - Item 11: The length of the school day, 1963; Publication (Box 369, Folder 4)
  - Item 12: The Teacher and medicare, 1963; Publication (Box 369, Folder 4)
  - Item 13: Urgently needed, a program to provide adequate finances for American Public Education, 1963; Publication (Box 369, Folder 4)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: City schools ask $13,750,000 more, Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: Teacher 'strike' stirs board head, Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: No pay rise in '50 Teachers are told, Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: Walkout, walkup, Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: The Mayor cuts, Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Jansen is rebuked by head of board for school 'strike', Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Draper and Adler termed traitors, Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 8: Teachers parade for a rise in pay, Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 9: Jansen is reubked by head of board for school 'strike', Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 10: Teachers protest against the City's way of adjusting salaries to new state funds, Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 11: Jansen reluctant to smash 'strike', Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 12: Eisenhower cites lack of teachers, Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 13: Mayor seeks root of school strife, Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 14: Extra job 'strike' voted by teachers, Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 15: NY Teachers use boycott weapon, Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 16: 2 teachers groups hold 'strike' is on, Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 17: Teachers fight city pay boost plan ..., Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 18: City hall stormed by 3,000 students, Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 19: 3,000 pupils storm City Hall..., Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 20: Appeal to City teachers, Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Item 21: 10,000 pupils defy Police in 'strikes' backing teachers, Publication (Box 370, Folder 1)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 370, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Survey of recent earned degress, Publication (Box 370, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Education around the world, Publication (Box 370, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Selected opinions concerning the National defense education act, Publication (Box 370, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: Superintendents' salaries, Publication (Box 370, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: Per pupil cost in representative districts of America, Publication (Box 370, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: Historical justification for Federal aid to education, Publication (Box 370, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: A nation-wide sample of classroom needs, Publication (Box 370, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: A summary of districts providing fringe benefits for teachers, Publication (Box 370, Folder 2)
  - Item 9: Examples of payroll deductions, Publication (Box 370, Folder 2)
  - Item 10: An educational ranking of the states, Publication (Box 370, Folder 2)
  - Item 11: Evaluation of personnel practices in selected school systems, Publication (Box 370, Folder 2)
  - Item 12: Examples of payroll deductions, Publication (Box 370, Folder 2)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 370, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: The 87th Congress, Publication (Box 370, Folder 3)
  - Item 2: A sample study of teachers' freedom of choice in joining professional organizations, Publication (Box 370, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: A sample study of teachers' freedom of choice in joining professional organizations, Publication (Box 370, Folder 3)
  - Item 4: The Teacher and general education, 1961; Publication (Box 370, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: The Utilization of educators, 1961; Publication (Box 370, Folder 3)
  - Item 6: A brief historical review of the American Federation of Teachers' fight for integration, 1961; Publication (Box 370, Folder 3)
  - Item 7: A brief review of certain current thoughts that affect curriculum and teachers, 1961; Publication (Box 370, Folder 3)
  - Item 8: Atypical children in American education, 1961; Publication (Box 370, Folder 3)
  - Item 9: Current fears of teachers, Publication (Box 370, Folder 3)
  - Item 10: Discipline during the age of the new frontier, 1961; Publication (Box 370, Folder 3)
  - Item 11: Historical justification for Federal aid to education, 1961; Publication (Box 370, Folder 3)
    Notes: Revised edtion
  - Item 12: Recent major litigation concerning integration, 1961; Publication (Box 370, Folder 3)
  - Item 13: Some constitutional prohibitions against financial aid to private schools, 1961; Publication (Box 370, Folder 3)
    Author: Carl Megel; George S. Reuter
  - Item 14: Some current issues in industrial education, 1960; Publication (Box 370, Folder 3)
  - Item 15: Some constitutional prohibitions against financial aid to private schools, Publication (Box 370, Folder 3)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 370, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: A summary of districts providing fringe benefits for teachers, 1962; Publication (Box 370, Folder 4)
  - Item 2: A survey of legislative action in the state legislatures concerning education, 1962; Publication (Box 370, Folder 4)
  - Item 3: Superintendents' salaries, 1962; Publication (Box 370, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: A selected bibliography concerning merit rating, Publication (Box 370, Folder 4)
  - Item 5: Selected bibliography on the 1962-63 college debate topic, 1962-1963 (Box 370, Folder 4)
  - Item 6: The teacher and automation, 1962; Publication (Box 370, Folder 4)
  - Item 7: The teacher and grievance procedures, 1962; Publication (Box 370, Folder 4)
- Council of the State University Federation of Teachers, Publication (Box 370, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: An evaluation, Publication (Box 370, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: Comparison of the positions of the bargaining agents on women's rights a public service, Publication (Box 370, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: Questions frequently asked about SUFT, Publication (Box 370, Folder 5)
  - Item 4: Policy Statement, Publication (Box 370, Folder 5)
  - Item 5: Proposed contract - draft of a collective bargaining agreement between the State Univ. of NY College at and the Faculty Bargaining Agent, State University Federation of Teachers, Publication (Box 370, Folder 5)
  - Item 6: State University Federation of Teachers - Newsletter, Publication (Box 370, Folder 5)
  - Item 7: Let's face the facts about our schools, Publication (Box 370, Folder 5)
  - Item 8: Democracy in Education The Syracuse Federation of Teachers, Publication (Box 370, Folder 5)
- Teachers' Union of the City of New York, Publication (Box 370, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Education for one world: jobs, security, peace., 1945; Publication (Box 370, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: Safeguard their future, a rational approach to the problems of juvenile delinquency in wartime, 1943; Publication (Box 370, Folder 6)
  - Item 3: Schools for victory, 1942; Publication (Box 370, Folder 6)
  - Item 4: Get acquainted with the Teachers Unions, Publication (Box 370, Folder 6)
  - Item 5: Teachers Bulletin, Publication (Box 370, Folder 6)
    Notes: vol. 1, no. 1, 3
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: For human and social progress: UFTs role in the struggle for a more just and decent society, 1973-1995 (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - Item 2: For members only: a handbook of UFT membership benefits, Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
    Author: UFT (United Federation of Teachers)
  - Item 3: Where we stand, Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - Item 4: Bibliographical data, Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - Item 5: Critique of acting Superintendent's budget, 1963-1964 (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - Item 6: "We are writing to you because we know you want our schools to provide the bes possible education for your childen", Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - Item 7: "The purpose of this letter is to let you know that we intend to keep right on fighting until we are assured that our schools will be better", Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - Item 8: Mrs. Roosevelt there is another way, Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - Item 9: Community College Board of Trustees draws fire of teachers, Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - Item 10: New York Teacher Magazine Section - Teacher Evaluation - a teacher unionist's view by Sandra Feldman, Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
    Author: Sandra Feldman
  - Item 11: New York Teacher magazine - Accountability can be a meaningful process to help the schools by Sandra Feldman, Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - Item 12: Collective bargaining contract between United Federation of Teachers, and Board of Education, City of New York, Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - Item 13: Address: Collective bargaining negotiations in New York City, 1962-63, 1962-1963 (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - Item 14: The story of the UFT collective bargaining negotiations - AFT Convention, Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - Item 15: Before the joint legislative committee on industrial and labor conditions on the bills pertaining to amendments to section 108, Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - Item 16: Collective bargaining for teachers, Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - Item 17: "Again we thank all of you who did so much to make it possible for us to win our battle for collective bargaining status", Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
    Notes: correspondence
  - Item 18: Union Democracy in Action, Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - Item 19: The urban school crisis: interview with Albert Shanker, Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - Item 20: Where we stand, 1974; Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
    Notes: Albert Shanker columns in the New York times and Amsterdam news.
  - Item 21: Where we stand, 1973; Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
    Notes: Albert Shanker columns in the New York times
  - Item 22: Winning collective bargaining, Publication (Box 370, Folder 7)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 370, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Resolution No. 44 - submitted by Northern Valley Federation of Teachers Local #522, Publication (Box 370, Folder 8)
  - Item 2: Resolution No. 73 - submitted by Chicago Teachers Union Local No. 1, Publication (Box 370, Folder 8)
  - Item 3: Resolution No. 76 - submitted by New York Teachers Guild Local #2, Publication (Box 370, Folder 8)
  - Item 4: Resolution No. 100 - submitted by New York Teachers Guild, Local #2, Publication (Box 370, Folder 8)
  - Item 5: Resolution on the no-strike policy, Publication (Box 370, Folder 8)
  - Item 6: Confidential - Resolutions presented to the Thirtieth Annual Convention of the American Federation of Teachers, Publication (Box 370, Folder 8)
  - Item 7: Confidential - For Delegates only - not for publication - Resolutions presented to the Twenty-fifth Annual Convention of the American Federation of Teachers, Publication (Box 370, Folder 8)
- UFT (United Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 370, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: He leads his teachers up the down staircase by A. H. Raskin, 1967; Publication (Box 370, Folder 9)
    Author: A. H. Raskin
    Notes: New York Times Magazine, Sept. 3, 1967
  - Item 2: United Action, 1962; Publication (Box 370, Folder 9)
    Notes: Vol. 1, no. 3 (April 1962)
  - Item 3: Legislative Bulletin, Publication (Box 370, Folder 9)
  - Item 4: News from New York Teachers Guild - "Guild Executive Board reaches agreement with committee for action through unity to change name, organizational structure, and salary.", Publication (Box 370, Folder 9)
  - Item 5: Before the joint legislative committee on industrial and labor relations in the public service, Statement by United Federation of Teachers., Publication (Box 370, Folder 9)
  - Item 6: Making Collective Bargaining Work, Publication (Box 370, Folder 9)
  - Item 7: The bargaining victory in New York City, Publication (Box 370, Folder 9)
  - Item 8: UFT welfare fund dental plan, Publication (Box 370, Folder 9)
  - Item 9: Research for action, Publication (Box 370, Folder 9)
  - Item 10: Educational research for action, Publication (Box 370, Folder 9)
  - Item 11: Health and Welfare benefits, 1975-1977 (Box 370, Folder 9)
  - Item 12: Health and Welfare benefits, 1975-1977 (Box 370, Folder 9)
- UFT (United Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 371, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Legal Report (Central Conference of Teamsters), Publication (Box 371, Folder 1)
    Author: David Previant
  - Item 2: Handbook for Chapter Chairmen, Publication (Box 371, Folder 1)
    Notes: 2nd edition
  - Item 3: Information for new teachers, 1974; Publication (Box 371, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: Success of our social order depends on a strong labor movement, Publication (Box 371, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: The enduring relevance of the labor movement, Publication (Box 371, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Teacher unionism: a quiet revolution, Publication (Box 371, Folder 1)